<steps>
   <step id="data_collection_inventory" title="Data Collection and Initial Inventory">
      <goal>
         Execute data collection from user submitted files ensuring data existence and reliability. Artifacts: Data inventory checklist, raw dataset file verification; Acceptance: os.path.exists('./assets/housing.csv')==True and pd.read_csv('./assets/housing.csv').shape[0]>0.
      </goal>
      <verified_artifacts>
         <variable name="data_inventory_checklist">Inventory report of data files, text-based, completeness verification standards</variable>
         <variable name="raw_dataset">Raw housing dataset loaded into memory, dataframe type, non-empty standards</variable>
      </verified_artifacts>
      <required_variables>
         <variable name="user_submit_files">List of submitted files, external source</variable>
      </required_variables>
      <pcs_considerations>
         <predictability>Ensures presence of necessary data for modeling and hypothesis testing.</predictability>
         <computability>Establishes reproducible data loading steps and file verification logic.</computability>
         <stability>Mitigates risks of missing or corrupted data through completeness checks.</stability>
      </pcs_considerations>
   </step>
   <step id="data_structure_discovery" title="Exploring Data Structure and Organization">
      <goal>
         Analyze the structure of the housing dataset to identify columns, data types, and organizational hierarchy. Artifacts: Data structure report; Acceptance: Columns=['longitude','latitude','housing_median_age','total_rooms',...] and all(pd.api.types.is_dtype(df[col]) for col in df.columns).
      </goal>
      <verified_artifacts>
         <variable name="data_structure_report">Detailed overview of dataset columns, data types, and hierarchy, text-based standards</variable>
      </verified_artifacts>
      <required_variables>
         <variable name="raw_dataset">Loaded housing dataset dataframe, analysis input source</variable>
      </required_variables>
      <pcs_considerations>
         <predictability>Defines a clear organizational context for data exploration and predictive modeling.</predictability>
         <computability>Facilitates efficient and systematic data structure analysis steps.</computability>
         <stability>Ensures robustness against inconsistent or incorrect data formatting.</stability>
      </pcs_considerations>
   </step>
   <step id="variable_semantics_analysis" title="Variable Semantic Interpretation">
      <goal>
         Map the semantics of each dataset column to business concepts and assess measurement scales. Artifacts: Variable semantic dictionary; Acceptance: len(variable_mapping)==len(df.columns) and all([type(scale) in [str, tuple] for scale in scales]).
      </goal>
      <verified_artifacts>
         <variable name="variable_mapping_report">Mapping of columns to business concepts, dictionary type, business logic alignment</variable>
         <variable name="measurement_scales">Scales and ranges of each dataset variable, dictionary type</variable>
      </verified_artifacts>
      <required_variables>
         <variable name="data_structure_report">Overview of dataset structure and columns, analysis input source</variable>
      </required_variables>
      <pcs_considerations>
         <predictability>Identifies meaningfully interpretable variables for downstream predictive modeling.</predictability>
         <computability>Ensures a standard semantic framework linking machine-readable data to domain knowledge.</computability>
         <stability>Promotes robustness in modeling by accounting for variable scale sensitivity.</stability>
      </pcs_considerations>
   </step>
   <step id="observation_unit_identification" title="Define Observation Units and Unique Identifiers">
      <goal>
         Identify observation unit types and ensure uniqueness within the dataset. Artifacts: Observation unit definition document; Acceptance: len(set(df.index)) == len(df.index) and 'observation_unit_type' in globals().
      </goal>
      <verified_artifacts>
         <variable name="observation_unit_definition">Detailed description of observation types, text-based</variable>
         <variable name="unique_identifiers">List of unique keys identifying observations, list type</variable>
      </verified_artifacts>
      <required_variables>
         <variable name="data_structure_report">Overview of dataset structure and relationships, source</variable>
      </required_variables>
      <pcs_considerations>
         <predictability>Enables clear identification of data representativeness and observation uniqueness.</predictability>
         <computability>Provides consistent methods for indexing and accessing data observations.</computability>
         <stability>Improves data utility by ensuring robust observation unit definitions.</stability>
      </pcs_considerations>
   </step>
   <step id="variable_relevance_assessment" title="Evaluate Variable Relevance">
      <goal>
         Assess relationships between variables and their relevance to predicting housing prices. Artifacts: Variable analysis report; Acceptance: len(relevant_variables) > 5 and sorted(relevance_scores, reverse=True)[0] >= threshold.
      </goal>
      <verified_artifacts>
         <variable name="relevance_scores">List of variable importance metrics, numerical standards</variable>
         <variable name="relevant_variables">Filtered list of predictive variable names, list type</variable>
      </verified_artifacts>
      <required_variables>
         <variable name="raw_dataset">Housing dataset loaded into memory, input source</variable>
         <variable name="variable_mapping_report">Semantic mappings for understanding variables, source</variable>
      </required_variables>
      <pcs_considerations>
         <predictability>Ensures identification of impactful predictive variables aligned with domain logic.</predictability>
         <computability>Enables systematic computational ranking of variable importance via quantitative metrics.</computability>
         <stability>Validates robustness by analyzing complementary and redundant variable effects.</stability>
      </pcs_considerations>
   </step>

   <focus>
   Each step is focused on ensuring that data required for predictive modeling of housing prices is comprehensively inventoried, structurally analyzed, semantically mapped, uniquely identified, and effectively connected with PSC considerations, enabling later stages with ideal inputs.
   </focus>
   <goals>
Establish the confidence of foundational dataset correctness by ensuring all initial checks, validations, mappings, and interpretations are complete and quality compliant.
   </goals>
</steps>